Erik Mayes

01000101 01110010 01101001 01101011 00100000 01001101 01100001 01111001 01101010 01110011

321-301-3169 | emayes528@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/erik-mayes-4aa8a41b5/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Strategic leader with 10+ years of experience managing large, diverse teams. Proven ability to motivate, mentor, and grow individuals. Transitioning from a successful career in retail to pursue a lifelong passion in computer science, with strong problem-solving skills and a drive for continuous learning.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

Orlando, FL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Full-Time) | Fourth-Year Student | GPA: 3.5

2024 - Present

Indian River State College

Fort Pierce, FL

Associate in Arts Degree | GPA: 3.5

2023 - 2024

Valencia Community College

Orlando, FL

Associate in Arts Degree

2008 -2010

SKILLS

- Proficient: Java, C, SQL, Linux, Git
- Experience with: Html, CSS, JavaScript, Python

PROJECTS

MIPS Assembly Programming Project

- Developed a low-level program in MIPS assembly, including instruction formats, memory addressing, and control flow
- Gained hands-on experience with registers, stack operations and system calls

Harvard CS50x | Online

- https://github.com/emayes505/CS50-Harvard-Online-Course.git
- · Flagship introductory computer science course

PERSONAL WEBSITE

- Website: #(website link)
 - Gained hands-on experience in designing, developing, and deploying responsive, user-friendly websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and basic web hosting tools.

EMPLOYMENT

CVS Pharmacy

Retail Store Manager | Indialantic FL, Vero Beach FL

04/2018 - 01/2022

• Led, trained, and successfully developed teams totaling over 80 employees across multiple locations, improving performance, morale, and customer satisfaction.

- Ensured compliance with ADA regulations and company standards while driving performance in customer service, sales, margin, and employee training to meet key metric goals.
- Mentored and developed colleagues, by building their confidence and skills, directly guiding two into store manager roles and over 10+ others in achieving promotions across various levels.

Store Manager in Training | Melbourne, FL

08/2016-04/2018

- Developed strong leadership and team-building skills
- Supported daily operations by overseeing inventory management, implementing loss prevention strategies, and driving sales performance

Shift Supervisor / Cashier | Orlando, FL

07/2009-07/2016

HONORS/AWARDS

CVS Pharmacy | Indialantic FL, Vero Beach FL

Paragon Winner

2018

• Recognized for outstanding performance, leading the top-performing store among 15 locations in sales, customer service and operational efficiency metric